Following a herd can be dangerous at
times cuz a lot of times people see
retail investors as you know sheep or
dumb money and these kind of like words
that people look down at us as normal
investors but we're a smart group.
>> Do you think the money printer is going
to be on soon?
>> Governments have a a bad habit I think
of just printing money.
>> What sort of metrics do you look at that
tells you we are about to head into a
bare market? You see
>> what indicators can we learn from large
trading platforms that may show us where
markets are headed next? E Toro is here
to join us today to discuss this theme
and the financial market system. Andrew
McCor is head of E Toro US. I'm David
Lynn.
>> Bonnie Chang from Bonnie Blockchain.
>> Andrew, so good to see you. Welcome to
the show.
>> Yeah, thanks so much for having me. Joy
to be here. You just had a panel and
that that talks about retail investors
versus Wall Street. Um, this cycle in
crypto, we hear that people do not like
VC coins because of different reasons.
Can you break it down for us?
>> Yeah, this is a topic I'm like probably
too nardily excited to talk about
because I I come from Wall Street. I was
a Bitcoin fanatic um and loved it and it
was a hobby, a passion and I was working
at a a large Wall Street bank and I
decided about three and a half years ago
to turn that passion into a career and
made the jump to it Toro. But I love the
fact that I lived in both worlds and
sometimes these worlds are a little
feisty and they don't like each other.
But I'm a big believer that in the world
of crypto and Bitcoin and blockchain, we
have a huge opportunity ahead of us and
a lot of challenges and a lot of
obstacles and sometimes we're building
the airplane as we're flying it. And the
more people we can have in the Bitcoin
tent, the Bitcoin party, the blockchain
family, I think is helpful. So whether
that's an OG libertarian like Bitcoin is
going to change the world or if it's a
new novice investor who've heard about
it or a Wall Street firm who wants to
build and innovate like welcome
everybody because we're trying to change
a whole financial system and it takes a
lot of people to do that.
>> Can you describe the difference between
you know Wall Street and retail
investors? How do they invest
differently? The psychology behind this.
>> Yeah. So I think you know in retail
investors there's probably more emotion
>> right? So like if you see stuff going up
you're more likely to get excited and if
you see stuff going down maybe you panic
maybe you sell quickly. Most of my
financial investing regrets are tied to
emotion. Um I sold Bitcoin at $3,000
once and you know at the time I was like
okay I got out because it gone down it
dipped up. Um and I regret that at the
time now. Um where's Wall Street? They
have teams of traders, scores of data,
and there's probably less emotion
because it's not your money. It's not
your retirement accounts, your kids
college savings. So, less emotion. But I
think I love like the fact that a place
like e Toro, right, where people cannot
just invest in crypto and stocks, but
you can see tons of data, what other
people are doing on the platform, their
performance, people sharing ideas. I
think that's really helpful to make more
thoughtful decisions, not always driven
by emotion. And I think this is the huge
opportunity with AI that a retail user
can take shortcuts in terms of like all
the data out there, learn quicker, learn
faster, and maybe take a little bit
emotion out of the investing game. It
can make it more fun, but also a little
more dangerous at times. You know,
Michael Sailor um a couple days ago had
a panel and he said if you go on a
street and ask a hundred 100 people if
you should do something and if 99 people
say do it, don't do it.
>> Powerful. Yeah.
>> But what about the data thing? So if you
see everybody is doing something,
does that mean don't do it?
>> I don't I wouldn't go I mean it's hard
to disagree with Michael Sailor, right?
is very successful and done so much for
our industry. But I think sometimes it's
good to be uh different and unique,
right? I love in my own life, I like
being a bit of a oddball, like wearing
bright clothes at a conference,
financial conference, those kind of
things.
>> You and Max Kaiser need to have a a
wardrobe show off.
>> Okay. All right. I love it. Um but you
know so following a herd can be
dangerous at times but at the same time
like you know if a lot of people are
doing something doesn't mean it's
automatically right but maybe it takes
some of the risk down but if you are a
believer and you're set on something
yeah stand your ground be yourself don't
follow the herd but if you're think like
a new investor you're new to the space
you're checking things out
see what other people are doing learn
what they're doing learn from their
mistakes like mine right um and I Pik
Tor is a great place people can could do
that and maybe you grow in your
confidence this time and you can make
those make those stands in unique
positions. So
>> we're going to talk about your IPO that
happened in May. Uh but before that I'm
just curious how much of etor's current
trading volume is crypto and how has
that ratio changed over the last couple
years?
>> Yeah, a large majority of it is is
crypto but we're really proud of the
fact it's becoming more and more
diversified each month, each year, each
week, right? So in the US alone a couple
years ago it was 100% crypto. uh early
2022 we started stocks and ETFs and then
later in 2022 brought on options
trading. So in the US it's probably
about half now whereas a couple
>> interesting because a lot of other
companies like Robin Hood for example
started with the reverse.
>> They're multi-asset with traditional
financial products and then expanded to
crypto. Why was the strategy different?
>> Yeah, I think because we're we're OG's
in the crypto space. We started doing
Bitcoin trading in 2013, a long time
ago. our founder, Yonyi, he was actually
at the very first Bitcoin conference a
long time ago when it probably fit in
this room as opposed to the giant stage
room out there. So, I think crypto is
like our heartbeat, our DNA, but we're
passionate about capital markets and
giving investors choice and freedom and
along the way added more asset classes.
And I think if we're talking in two more
years, I think we in the US will have
added even more asset classes um to just
give people that diversified offering.
But we're we're passionate about crypto
and it'll be a huge part of what we do.
But over time, I think the percentages
will go down just because we're doing
more and offering more services to
customers.
>> You know, a lot of people say crypto
people are more, you know, they hunt the
risk. They want the risk. Um, is that
what you're seeing on your platform? Um,
crypto people, they tend to do crazier
stuff, but stock people, they're more
conservative. Is that what you're
seeing? I think it's a mix of both.
There's definitely the the yolo traders,
which I think is is cool. Like, if you
want to just take a small part of your
money and take a big gamble and hope for
a better life, that's that's cool. I
think people should have that
empowerment to make those kind of
choices.
>> I think what's really exciting to see,
especially in the last couple months, is
are people taking more risks, but
they're very thoughtful about it. So
earlier in the year, one day when the
Nvidia deepseek news came out and Nvidia
stock crashed, like suddenly had like a
lot of trading volumes in Nvidia that
day. And I think as people are thinking
like, hey, I think the market reaction
is wrong here. Like this is a great
company with a great history and a new
story came out over the weekend of maybe
a new company that's a threat out there,
but we're in this for the long term. So
let's buy our favorite stock at a big
discount suddenly. And in the last
couple months with tariffs on, tariffs
off, some tariffs on, all the noise and
chaos, a lot of our users were really
thoughtful about buying a dip and taking
that risk, which is really cool to see
because a lot of times people see retail
investors as, you know, maybe sheep or
dumb money and these kind of like words
that people look down at us as normal
investors, but we're a smart group and
we're thoughtful and you take risk and
that's not a bad thing.
Total crypto market cap surpassed $3.5
trillion uh recently. Total trading
daily trading volume hit $171 billion.
So new all-time highs. How much of this
is speculative mania versus sustainable
growth? In other words, are there
indicators on your platform in
particular that would indicate people
are taking longerterm positions or are
they short-term trading? Yeah, we have a
lot of buy and hold investors and going
back to the prior comment, like I think
people are being very thoughtful, right?
So, if you see your favorite crypto or
your favorite stock or ETF have that big
price decline, you're passionate about
it, like it's a great time to to buy it,
to get it on sale. And it's the same
concept if you go to your favorite shoe
store, clothing store, food restaurant,
and stuff's on sale. You get excited,
right? And you're like, "This is the
pair of shoes I wanted." And suddenly
it's 10% off, 20% off. like this is a
great discount and I think more and more
retail investors are starting to think
about stocks in the same way. So you're
passionate about a brand a company and
suddenly because of some news the price
goes down
>> but I'm committed to it in the long term
let's let's scoop it up.
>> What type of metrics do you look at that
tells you we are about to head into a
bare market?
>> Oh I wish I knew that. Um I think you
know you you see different times where
maybe there's less dip buying, right? um
and less trading activity, especially in
the last couple months, you know,
there's a lot of the buying of the dips
over and over, but each
>> each time it got a little bit less,
right, with each tariff news, but then
we saw a huge spike up and crypto, I
think it's telling where we will have
these quoteunquote crashes, right? But I
remember when a crash went from 20 to
3,000 in the last couple months, we've
gone from 110 down to 78, right? And the
fact that these lows are repeatedly
higher I think is encouraging. I think a
important sign when we start seeing new
lows that are going the other way,
right? If say if Bitcoin in a couple
months from now crashes to 73 instead of
78 and it recovers and it goes to 66 and
and so on. But markets go up, markets go
down, but the general trend in the last
few years especially is uh a line going
up and to the right. Well, I suppose if
people buy a lot of short selling
instruments, if the put call ratio is
high, if the volume for let's say
inverse ETFs is high, you know, that
could be an indicator, but you're not
seeing that. There's there's some of
that for sure, but the overall sentiment
and we see that both in trading data,
but we also do these quarterly surveys
called the retail investor beat where
we're going to thousands of retail
investors and asking them the topics of
the day, whether it's politics, markets,
technology, news, AI. And we see that in
those results as well in these surveys
that people overall are bullish and
encouraged. And I think because we've
lived through a lot, right? Like a lot
of retail investors today, you probably
heard about or you lived through the
financial crisis and these huge scary
bad times. And then people who's, you
know, they're committed and invested in
those moments like did really well in
the last 15 years even during the COVID
era, right? World's falling apart. It's
chaos. It's crazy. Markets take and then
we saw what happened. And so even when
bad news is coming, I think people get
like over the long run markets recover.
entrepreneurs are doing amazing things
in our country and around the world
building cool stuff and um that's
encouraging.
>> Given your background, do you think the
money printer is going to be on soon?
>> Yeah, good question. Governments have a
a bad habit, I think, of just printing
money over and over again and to kind of
get us out of trouble at times and I
think long term it leads us to to more
trouble, right? We have almost $40
trillion in, you know, federal debt in
the in the United States. And is that
sustainable? I don't know. But I I
suspect the printer will be turned on at
some point again. And I think that's
where the huge value of Bitcoin lies.
And that's how I got into the space. My
dad is like he's a true believer and
doesn't like money printing and all this
kind of stuff. So ironic, it's my dad
who got me into Bitcoin. Usually it's
like the opposite.
>> Tell us the story.
>> Yeah. So he retired and he found
YouTube. But YouTube, this is like 2013.
This is not like when YouTube's new. And
you know, he found himself down the
rabbit hole of two different things. And
one was Bitcoin and the other was pickle
ball. And so like in 2013, my dad is
like talking about Bitcoin all the time,
talking about pickle ball all the time.
And like I didn't know what any of this
was. And for years and years, he's like,
"This is awesome. This is great. do
this. Now, my dad like I guess is f very
fashion forward and I never knew uh was
right about Bitcoin
>> and right about pickle ball as it's like
consumed the whole world and tennis
courts are becoming pickle ball courts
and so he got into the space for this
money printing kind of and deficit
concerns and that's what originally um
got me into the space because I love the
idea it's a currency built by people
operated by people and not just the
handful of people in the government.
E Toro's IPO. Let's talk about that. So
11.9 million shares offered uh in May.
Has this changed your strategic
priorities at all now that we're you're
publicly listed on the NASDAQ?
>> Yeah, not a not a huge change. You know,
it's been a huge goal for us for a long
time and it's something that's I think
especially important and special to us
because we are a platform that's been
breaking down barriers to investing
around the world for 18 years and trying
to make capital markets accessible to
everyday investors. And so it is a great
honor and joy to become a publicly
traded company that even our users can
invest in. Um so that is a big moment
for us.
>> What's the trading volume of e Toro on e
Toro?
>> Uh we haven't looked at that some but we
can't talk a ton about stuff around our
stock but all right um but it's it's
really special to think the customers
who've been with us some 18 years are
now owners of the very company. And I
think that's a powerful moment. But in
terms of our priorities, like you know,
we want to empower investors, create
products that help people get engaged
and make financial markets more
accessible. And whether we're publicly
traded or a private company, those
priorities are still the same, but maybe
it gives us more opportunities to do
some more cool and innovative stuff when
you have capital markets behind you.
>> How do you pick what to list, especially
when it comes to meme coins and altcoins
>> on in the crypto space?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So we have a very diligent like
review committee and process where first
we do like the technical review and
learn about the founders, the assets,
the protocols, the governance, the
history, their social media and lots of
factors, right? Um and then we take it
to not just the business and tech folks
but the legal and compliance people who
weigh in and look at it through a
different lens to make sure this would
be an appropriate asset and it doesn't
violate any laws. and here in the US
that's a bigger topic than in in some
other jurisdictions. So we look at it
through that lens as well and things
like the market cap the liquidity and
once it goes through those various
processes we're uh we we'll list it on
the platform but then we continue to do
monitoring as we go. It's not just a
list it and forget it. We have ongoing
processes where we're looking at
negative news. We're looking at
liquidity, trading volumes to making
sure that the things that we're offering
our customers like are are appropriate
and not scandalous or anything like
that. And it's their choice if they want
to use their money to buy them or not.
>> Do you care about trading volume and
narratives? Uh meaning a lot of
exchanges they in Asia, they type they
kind of like copy each other. So they
see that you list something and the
trading volume's crazy, they'll list it
right away. Do you do that or is the
culture different?
>> Yeah, we definitely look at peer firms
to see what they're doing and I think
that's an important benchmark but it'll
never be our like deciding factor. Um
it's so that's a important element and I
think especially on the legal compliance
regulatory it gives you added comfort if
all your peer firms are doing the same
thing almost like a check the box in
sense of like okay I think our diligence
analysis is landing in the right spot
but um you know we we're proud to offer
globally like 120 I think crypto assets
in the US we're now 15 and growing and
we'll look to our peers but when we
believe something's right we'll goes
through the right process we'll
certainly list it. You know how I um
picture crypto deent day. They'll be in
pajamas and they'll be in front of their
computer all day. And what is your day
like?
>> Cuz you are in crypto, but you're also
>> in Wall Street like how does that two
world
>> combine? Yeah, my day is crazy. I have I
have four precious kids and so my days
start really really early and we have
like lots of different bus pickups and
bus stop duties. Uh so usually ends with
some kind of kids starts with kids chaos
and u we have a global team around the
world and so a lot of very early
mornings and meetings and I love living
in both worlds. I love hanging out with
the crypto degenerates, you know, which
they embrace, right? And that's kind of
my origin story in crypto, but I also
love like going to Wall Street events
and talking to them about it, educating
them about the the platform, the
protocols, the opportunities. And it's
super cool to see the evolution on that
side. Like just in March on St.
Patrick's Day went to one of the largest
banks, one of the oldest banks in the
world had like a crypto St. Patrick's
Day happy hour in New York City.
>> This is not happening last year. This is
not happening a year before. And seeing
that evolution and change, I think it's
like really exciting. Some of the dgens
don't love it, right, of Wall Street
coming into the space, like I mentioned
before, like the bigger we can make this
movement,
I think it's going to be better for for
the whole community. The Genius Act
passed on May 20th uh stable coin bill.
Um has that affected uh trading uh
patterns on e Toro at all?
>> Uh not yet. So at least in the US we
don't offer stable coins. Certainly
something in the future we would like to
do. And you know it's nice to see some
crypto legislation advanced. There's
still some final hurdles for it to
actually um get passed and put into law.
But I've been I've been in this space
since 2017 and I think every year I've
told colleagues, friends, peers, family
that think crypto legislation's coming
this year, this year. And I've been
wrong the last like seven years, but I'm
convinced
>> this year it's going to happen. And that
is a huge opportunity for the industry
because right now a lot of our laws here
in the US are based from the 1930s,
right? And you'll hear in the US like
the Howie test and the Howie case. This
is a 1946 Supreme Court case about
orange trees
>> and how we're putting stuff like crypto
assets and memecoins into that kind of
structure. It's not healthy or
productive. So definitely eager for
legislation, thoughtful regulation. I
think it's going to be a massive moment
for the industry. Well, can you give us
some examples of maybe some challenges
that you faced regarding um listing from
the SEC or even CFTC that you can
comment on and how ETOR has overcome
these challenges?
>> Yeah. So, we we settled a case with the
SEC last fall, right? The SEC under the
prior administration sued a lot of
firms,
>> right? And we we made a decision to
settle it and move past it. It was on a
neither admit nor deny basis. It was
voluntary. We thought let's just move
past this and we want to go through the
IPO process. We'll focus on that and
then when the time is right we're going
to go through our crypto diligence
analysis is how we test and the
different factors and start listing
crypto assets again. So as part of the
settlement we went from originally 27
crypto assets down to three. Now we took
a big step yesterday adding 12 more. So
we're up at 15. And the goal is to keep
adding more and more assets and give
customers those options. Um, just like
we do overseas in other countries where
over 100 different assets,
>> a lot of companies IPOed, well, not a
lot, but several companies in the crypto
space IPOed in the last month, including
Circle.
>> Uh, Coinbase didn't IPO, but they joined
the S&P 500.
>> This is just interesting timing. Can you
just comment on that coincidence or not?
It's a it's a huge moment where we're
seeing this world of like crypto and
traditional finance are merging and I'm
really passionate about being one of
those connectors to help to close those
gaps. Um because I think in five years
like the panel I spoke on earlier like
Wall Street and crypto investors or Wall
Street and and crypto and blockchain
it's not a panel anymore. It's just
finance. It all is going to merge into
one. Uh but e Toro, our IPO, we're
really proud to be one of the first um
IPOs in the crypto space, but also
fintech space in a long time since I
think Robin Hood and Coinbase were 2021
and there really hasn't been any since
then. So we we're proud to kick down
that door and we hope more and more
firms will follow because I think it
adds more legitimacy, the legitimacy,
trust uh and capital to an industry that
um can change the world. When you say
traditional finance and crypto being
one, right? Back in the days, we used to
hear people say, "Oh, Bitcoin is a
currency and we will buy things with
Bitcoin and then Bitcoin becomes this
store of value, digital gold." Uh,
looking well 10 year in the future, what
would it look like when you say they
kind of merge together?
>> Yeah, I think the biggest example I can
think of is in the world of stocks and
ETFs. So if you today, you know, you
might buy your Target shares, Nike
shares, Apple shares, Chipotle shares,
whatever it may be. I think 5 years or
less, that's all on the blockchain.
>> And what I hope happens is right now,
like if you want to buy Chipotle stock
and you put in your order and it goes to
market centers or exchanges, and there's
all this stuff behind the scenes and
someone else somewhere is like selling
their shares to you. But I believe in a
world one day, you know, if I body like
I want to sell a share in a company, you
want to buy it, I can just send it to
you directly on a blockchain, not going
through all these intermediaries and
different firms. And we can do it any
day of the week, any time of the day.
And I think that's that's where we're
headed. It's going to be hard to get
there over time, but I think eventually,
you know, traditional investing is going
to be on a blockchain. Um, finishing off
for me, I I'd like to know what the
future of exchanges is going to look
like. Specifically for E Toro, for
example, how are you integrating, let's
say, AI into your platform? What kind of
new features are you launching that will
that will satisfy changing investor and
traders appetites? Um, what's next? How
are you integrating new technology?
>> Yeah, we are passionate about AI and so
we use it all the time behind the
scenes. We even have hackathons where we
encourage our employees to like build
cool stuff with AI. Uh give us ideas and
I think they even paid us like $250 per
employee to like submit ideas. And so we
are thinking about it constantly. I
think the dream is at one point you're
going to open an e Toro app and whether
you want to just click the the stock you
want to buy or you want to turn over to
AI and let them suggest for you. I think
that's going to be option. The Gator
Toro is very uniquely situated because
you don't just have trading data, but we
have what people are talking about on
the platform, what they're liking or
commenting on different posts, what news
articles are sharing. So you also get
that like social emotional side and we
have 30 million registered users around
the world and that's a lot of unique
data and we're I think we're going to
use that data in cool ways to empower
investors who are looking for ideas,
trends, opportunities, moments. Um,
unfortunately you can't always just snap
your fingers and launch a product,
especially in the US because there's a
lot of regulations in here.
>> Can you can you give us an example of
something that people are talking about
what's trending right now in that in
that?
>> I think you're going to see probably
overseas first and then eventually US
like portfolios that are created by AI
and that are driven by what people on
the platform are buying and the timing
and it might be things that are positive
sentiment, negative negative sentiment.
So I think you're going to see AIdriven
portfolios and probably ideas where like
if you you know show an interest in one
stock AI is going to populate like other
trading ideas for you but we just want
to do that in a compliant and regulatory
kind of framework matter and
>> um exciting times ahead and I think E
Toro is uniquely positioned for that. So
>> if I assume AI is this genius and
everyone's using AI to trade who makes
money.
>> Yeah. So, I wouldn't turn it over to AI
quite yet. And this is uh last fall. I'm
passionate about like my kids learning
about investing. It's something like I
didn't know anything about growing up.
And so, we actually had a family
investing contest. We each had $50. We
picked our favorite stocks, ETFs,
cryptos. At the end of like a month or
two, we saw who did the best and
actually had a chatbt portfolio as well
and asked ChatCBT like what would you
invest in? And I'm proud to say like I I
won a contest which isn't maybe saying a
lot when it's a 5-year-old and a
nine-year-old but actually beat Chachi
BT as well. It was uh some plain vanilla
type items of you know big Dow type only
companies and um I think with AI it's
going to help investors a lot but you
still got to make your own decisions and
doing your own research but AI can
really help with that research and
cutting things down. I want to go back
to our earlier question about how stock
market will be on the blockchain. First
argument I've heard people say is we
don't need stock market on the
blockchain. Um second is Wall Street is
not going to allow that because then you
remove the middleman which are the
institutions. How do they make money? Uh
what do you say to that?
>> Yeah, things change really quick, right?
So on e Toro today, you can buy your
favorite stock as little as $10, zero
commissions. This is unheard of like 6
years ago. So up until like 2019, most
almost all other than one, all the big
trading platforms in the US, some didn't
have an apps. You're still like on a
desktop or talking to someone, but you'd
have to to buy stock, you'd pay like $8,
$10 per commission. You'd have to buy a
full share and not accessible for normal
investors. And that whole world now 5
years later seems ancient.
>> So if you think like five years from now
something like you know architecture of
how it's set up today I think is going
to feel ancient. Um and Wall Street and
financial firms will find a way to make
money and look for efficiencies and you
have teams of um analysts. There's you
have that that firepower to do just
that. But it doesn't make sense that if
I want to buy something and you want to
sell it, it's got to go through like 20
different firms along the way. I should
be able to buy and sell something like
directly any time of the day. And it's
going to be hard to build that, but I
think eventually that's going to be our
system.
>> Thanks, Andrew. Great chat.
>> Yeah. Thanks so much. Appreciate it.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. Thank you. You too.